

ABOUT ME

A recruitment and sourcing specialist, having around 8+ years of enriched experience in hiring IT & Non-IT professionals across the globe.

I am a Portal & Social Media sourcing expert currently hiring for diversified roles in and around different cities of Europe & APJ. I also assist business and leadership with Market intelligence.

EDUCATION

CMR Institute of Technology

Master of Business Administration

NSHM College of Management & Tech

Bachelor of Insurance & Risk Management

CONTACT



🖂 Arindamdeb3000@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/arindamdeb/



ARINDAM DEB

WORK EXPERIENCE

Akamai Technologies / March 2021 - present

Talent Sourcing & Research Specialist II

☼ France ☼ Poland ۞ Japan ۞ Australia ۞ Singapore
۞ Netherlands ۞ Germany ۞ Spain ۞ UK & I

- Driving sourcing strategies & research for APJ & EMEA Region as per GDPR compliance
- Driving Market intelligence for leadership and business
- Driving sourcing from Social Media platforms with 0% Job portal usage
- I know to get my job done by sourcing through web platforms like GitHub, StackOverflow, MeetUp, Reddit, Kaggle, Xing, Slack, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, etc.
- I don't use #Recruit'em to write my X-Rays. I always build my own strings
- I have my own SSaR Page, where I have customized some handpicked tools to make my Sourcing job easier
- · Creating visually attractive content for the best outreach
- Create and execute a recruiting strategy, which results in a top-tier, qualified talent pool of professionals and a strong candidate pipeline
- Develop and execute a sourcing strategy, pre-screen candidates, and deliver pre-qualified diverse candidates to hiring managers
- Partner with the hiring manager and recruiters
- Grow existing network, foster new relationships, and attend networking events to further identify talent for the organization
- May contribute to projects as part of the long-term strategy of building a best-in-class product organization

Akamai Technologies via. Randstad / October 2019 - February 2021

Talent Sourcer - EMEA

- Driving sourcing strategies & research for EMEA Region as per GDPR compliance
- · Creating visually attractive content for the best outreach
- I do Create and execute recruiting strategies, which results in a top-tier, qualified talent pool of professionals and a strong candidate pipeline I grow existing networks, foster new relationships, and attend networking events to further identify talent for the organization

CGI / May 2018 - October 2019

Specialist - APJ & India

- Driving Niche & Leadership positions for all BU's
- Driving Diversity & Inclusion initiative of all BU's
- · Responsible for Recruitment Marketing all BU's
- · Create and execute a recruiting strategy, which results in a top-tier, qualified talent pool of professionals and a strong candidate pipeline
- Develop and execute a sourcing strategy, pre-screen candidates, and deliver pre-qualified diverse candidates for the hiring manager's evaluation
- Partner with the hiring manager to identify the role of the interview team, assign competencies using both technical and behavioral interviewing
- · Grow existing network, foster new relationships, and attend networking events to further identify talent for the organization
- · May contribute to projects as part of the long-term strategy of building a best-in-class staffing organization
- · Mentoring recruitment team to upscale their sourcing skills
- · Create Market Intelligence for businesses to help them in RFP's
- Perform Market Analytics for the team to do target-based sourcing
- Organize Social Media Recruitment campaigns to attract a talent pool
- Building recruitment strategy & road-map
- Organizing webinars and hackathons to engage the CGI Talent Community
- Partner with Campus team to execute firm-wide divisional & University Relations Strategies, events,s, etc.

L&T Technology Services / July 2017 - May 2018

Senior Executive - APJ , Middle East & KSA

- Handle independently end-to-end lateral Talent Acquisition requirements for APAC,ME & KSA
- Managed BU's across Japan, Australia, Malaysia, Singapore, S Korea, Thailand, China & ME
- Developed hiring approaches to meet Open Position requirements in a time-bound manner.
- Interacting with the hiring manager/s
- Profile hunting from various Job boards.
- Handled end to end business transactions with International/Domestic Associative Agencies
- Screened profiles received from Agency and liaise to provide transparency & feedback on time
- Submitted pre-screened profiles to the hiring team.
- Scheduled & Coordinated with the hiring team for Technical Interviews of shortlisted candidates.
- Ensured compliance with all company policies and other regulatory requirements.

CareerNet Technologies / July 2013 - July 2017

Consultant/ Associate Consultant - APJ & India

- Sourcing & Lead generation
- Client Management
- Resource Management
- Domestic & International recruitment Client Relationship
- Lead Generation
- Leadership Hiring
- Headhunting
- Market Intelligence
- Recruitment Marketing

Contact Address

Primary Address: #24 2nd Floor, Sri Sadashiva Temple Road RS Palya, Kammanahalli – Bangalore, Karnataka – 560033

Permanent Address: A-17 Bijoya Enclave, North loco Tank Near Saibaba Temple, Hirapur - Jharkhand, Dhanbad - 826001